<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="000style.xsl"?>
<teiCorpus>
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Digitised and Encoded copy of Negro Slavery by Zachary MacAulay</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Transcribed from digital copy available from Recovered Histories at
                    http://www.recoveredhistories.org/pamphlet1.php?page=1&amp;orderby=MaxID&amp;catid=66</authority>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
                        <title>Negro Slavery; or, A View of Some of the More Prominent Features of
                            that State of Society, as it Exists in the United States of America and
                            in the Colonies of the West Indies, Especially in Jamaica</title>
                    </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Printed for Hatchard and Son, Piccadilly, and J. and A. Arch,
                            Cornhill</publisher>
                        <distributor>Sold Also by W. Graphel, Church street, and G. and J. Robison,
                            Castle Street, Liverpool.</distributor>
                        <date when="1823">1823</date>
                        <pubPlace>
                            <settlement>London</settlement>
                        </pubPlace>
                    </publicationStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <TEI>
        <teiHeader>
            <fileDesc>
                <titleStmt>
                    <title/>
                </titleStmt>
                <publicationStmt>
                    <authority>Transcribed by a student of Digital History at Sheffield Hallam
                        University</authority>
                </publicationStmt>
                <sourceDesc>
                    <bibl>
                        <biblScope>43</biblScope>
                    </bibl>
                </sourceDesc>
            </fileDesc>
        </teiHeader>
        <text>
            <body>adopting this conclusion on insufficient grounds, we shall specify some particulars, of vital importance to the well-being of the Negro reace, in which there is manifestly no real improvement. <p> 1. The Negroes in Jamaica are still driven at their work by the impulse of the carl-whip, as cattle or horses are driven in this country. - This fact is undeniable. But let us only consider for one moment all the depressing and brutalizing side effects of such a system, - a system which shuts out the Negro from even the pretence to a higher motive for exertion than the fear of the lash, and which extracts labour from him, not in the measure which his strength affords, or his interest prompts , but in the measure which an overseer or a driver may choose to draw from him by impending terror or the actual infliction of corporal punishment; - let us only consider this one feature of coloniad bondage, and we shall at once see enough to account for more than half od its multiplied evils.* <p> * The following description of the driving system has been given by one who was long an eye-witness of its practical operation. It is contained in a pamphlet, publishes by <persName key="Hatchard, William" from="1834" to="1912" role="Negro Philosopher" ref="http://www.website.com/webpage.html">Hatchard in 1802, entitled "The Crisis of the Sugar Colonies."(p.8-13.)<p> "That West India Slaves, whether French or English, are the property of their master, and transferable by him, like his inanimate effects; that in general he is absolute ariter of the extent and the mode of their labout, and of the quantity of subsistence to be given in return for it; and that they are disciplined and punished at his discretion, direct privation of life or member excepted : these are prominent features, and sufficiently known, of the state of slavery. Not is the manner in which the labour of the slaves is conducted a matter of less publicity. Everyman who has heard any thing of West Indian affairs, is aquainted with the term Negro-drivers, and knows, or may know, that the slaves, in their ordinary field-labours, are driven to their work, in the strict sense of the term 'driven' is used in Europe: though this statemnt no more involves an intimation, that, in practice, the lash is incessantly, or with any needless frequency, applied to their back , then the phrase  'to drive a team of horses' imports, that the waggoner is continually smacking his whip. <p>  
                
            </body>
        </text>
    </TEI>
</teiCorpus>
